A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs Division, Social Development, Office Files of Ronald T. Gault FA659
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, National Affairs Division, Social Development, Office Files of Ronald T. Gault
1969-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Gault, Richard T.
Ford Foundation
FA659
2.62 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Alphabetical.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Ronald T. Gault's career encompassed jobs in civil rights work, government, philanthropy, and investment banking. From 1969 to 1978, he worked at the Ford Foundation as a Program Officer in the Division of National Affairs, Social Development Program.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Gault became a senior advisor to New York City Mayor Ed Koch. He then became a Vice President at First Boston Corp. He later moved to Johannesburg, South Africa where he worked as CEO of business development and client relations for JP Morgan.
Gault earned a B.A. from Grinnell College and a master's degree from the University of Michigan. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Gault had jobs at the Urban League and later the Community Relations Service (CRS) within the United States Department of Justice. He is married to journalist and civil rights activist Charlayne Hunter-Gault who formerly served as CNN's Johannesburg bureau chief.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, reports and administrative records.
- Africa -- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Africa -- General, 1969 (Box 1)
- Africa -- Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 1)
- Immamu Baraka, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Immamu Baraka -- Congress of African People, 1970 September 3-7 (Box 1)
- Fort Lincoln Development Corporation, 1973 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 1)
- NEW Thing -- Grant Recommendation, 1972 (Box 1)
- NEW Thing -- Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
- Progress Venture Capital Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Resident Advisory Board (RAB) -- Notes and Telephone Communications, 1971-1974 (Box 1)
- RAB -- Proposal, 1971 (Box 1)
- RAB -- Monitoring Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Retreat -- National Affairs, 1971 February 10-13 (Box 1)
- Tenant Affairs Board (TAB) -- Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Notes, 1971 (Box 1)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Financial Management System, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Arthur Brazier, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Report, 1973 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Terence McCormack, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- K.S. Sweet Associates, 1973 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Hillman (Supermarket) -- Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Hillman's Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Woodlawn New Community, 1974 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Project Rehabilitation, 1973 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- JPT Reports, 1972 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Woodlawn Gardens Construction Defects, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Woodlawn Gardens -- Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Woodlawn Gardens -- Default, 1975 (Box 2)
- The Woodlawn Organization (TWO) -- Woodlawn Gardens -- Tax Assessment, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
- Watts Labor Community Action Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
- Zion Organization, 1974 (Box 2)
- Zion Arena, 1973 (Box 2)
- Zion Investment Association (ZIA), 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- ZIA -- Archon Capital Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Zion -- Conversion of Loan, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Zion -- Housing, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust (ZNPCT), 1975 (Box 2)